SANTIAGO TOLEDO-CORTÉS

Phone: (+57)3113784546 (+57)3194216664

e-mail: stoledoc@unal.edu.co

RESUME

Mathematician, Master in Applied Mathematics by the National University of Colombia. Ph.D. student in Systems and Computing Engineering. Ability to plan, control and evaluate projects, and to lead work teams. More than five years of experience in teaching in higher education. Experience in the design and implementation of algorithms and software in C++, Python, R and Matlab. More tan one year of research experience, member of the MindLab (Machine learning, perception and discovery Lab) research group, categorized A1 by Colciencias. Active researcher with publications in Machine Learning.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

UNIVERSIDAD DE LA SABANA SCHOOL OF ENGINEERING

DOCENTE PLANTA

Jan 2017 - Dec 2019

Full-time professor at Mathematics, Physics, and Statistics Department, at the Faculty of Engineering.

DOCENTE CÁTEDRA

Jan 2015 - Dec 2016

Part-time professor at Mathematics, Physics, and Statistics Department, at the Faculty of Engineering.

ESCUELA COLOMBIANA DE INGENIERÍA JULIO GARAVITO DEPARTMENT OF MATHEMATICS

DOCENTE CÁTEDRA

Jan 2016 - Dec 2016

Part-time professor at Mathematics Department.

UNIVERSIDAD NACIONAL DE COLOMBIA SCHOOL OF SCIENCES

BECARIO ASISTENTE DOCENTE – LECTURER

Aug 2013 - Nov 2014

Lecturer for two courses offered by the Department of Mathematics to the careers of Biology, Geology, Chemistry, Pharmaceutical Chemistry, Economics and careers of the Faculty of Engineering.

EDUCATION - RESEARCH

Ph. D. IN SYSTEMS AND COMPUTING ENGINEER

Proposal title: Computational Learning Model for the Eye Fundus Analysis to Support Medical Diagnosis

Awarded by Google LARA 2019

Advisor: Fabio A. Gonzalez O. Ph.D.

Universidad Nacional de Colombia - Bogotá

In process since Aug 2017

MASTER'S DEGREE IN APPLIED MATHEMATICS

Thesis: A Relativistic Model for a Global Navigation Satellite System Universidad Nacional de Colombia - Bogotá 2013 - 2015

BACHELOR DEGREE IN MATHEMATICS

Universidad Nacional de Colombia - Bogotá 2007 - 2012

PUBLICATIONS

 Santiago Toledo-Cortés, Iván Y. Castellanos-Martinez, Fabio A. Gonzalez. (2019). Large Scale Learning Techniques for Least Squares Support Vector Machines. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 11401.

RESEARCH GRUPS

 Member of the MindLab Research Grup - Machine Learning, Perception and Discovery Lab.
Cathegory A1 by Colciencias. Director: Fabio A. Gonzalez O. Official web site: https://ingenieria.unal.edu.co/mindlab/

ACADEMIC EVENTS

- 33rd Conference in Neural Information Processing Systems, NIPS 2019. Poster at LXAI Research Workshop: Large Scale Learning Techniques for Least Squares Support Vector Machines. Vancouver Convention Center, Vancouver, Canada, December 2019.
- First Colombian Conference of Applied and Industrial Mathematics MAPI1. Oral presentation: Evaluating Kernel Approximation Techniques for Large-Scale Learning. Universidad Nacional de Colombia and Universidad de Los Andes, Bogotá, Colombia, August 2018.
- 6th Doctoral Colloquium of the Faculty of Engineering. Poster: Evaluating Kernel Approximation Techniques for Large-Scale Learning. Universidad Nacional de Colombia, Bogotá, Colombia, May 2018.
- 5th Doctoral Colloquium of the Faculty of Engineering. Poster: Deep Kernel Learning Methods. Universidad Nacional de Colombia, Bogotá, Colombia, Nov 2017.
- 609. WE-Heraeus Seminar. Relativistic Geodesy, foundations and applications. Poster: Review of a Relativistic Model for a Global Navigation Satellite System. Physikzentrum, Bad Honnef, Germany, March 2016.

LANGUAGES

English – Level: C1German – Level: A2

Spanish – Native

SANTIAGO TOLEDO-CORTÉS